<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on chillu.com</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on chillu.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.chillu.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Contributions to Silverstripe CMS</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/silverstripe/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/silverstripe/</guid><description>Contributed nearly a thousand pull requests and collaborated with hundreds of community members on the many repos making up Silverstripe CMS (PHP and Javascript) since 2005 until today. Silverstripe is a product of over a hundred individual repos, and my contributions are scattered among them (see my github.com/silverstripe contribution timeline).
There were a few major areas of focus over the years for myself, with the help of many open source contributors:</description></item><item><title>Github Issue Ml Relevancy</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/github-issue-ml-relevancy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/github-issue-ml-relevancy/</guid><description>https://github.com/chillu/github-issue-ml-relevancy
Too many Github notifications, too little time. The obvious answer there is to spend lots of time creating a hyper personalised prediction engine that can tell me what I&amp;rsquo;m interested in. And learn a whole bunch of stuff on the way. This is a tongue-in-cheek experiment, which resulted in a realisation that I&amp;rsquo;m pretty unpredictable.
See it in action (predictions for the chillu github user):
http://github-issue-ml-relevancy.herokuapp.com
What does this do?</description></item><item><title>Github Issue Tracker</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/silverstripe-issue-tracker/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/silverstripe-issue-tracker/</guid><description>VueJS frontend to aggregate Github issues through their GraphQL API, deployed on Vercel</description></item><item><title>Property Trends Analysis Dashboard</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/property-trends-dashboard/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/property-trends-dashboard/</guid><description>https://github.com/chillu/property-viewer-shiny-dashboard
Applied data analysis to my own house hunting back in 2018. I choose to believe this was a factor in not over-paying for the house we bought (if that is even possible in the New Zealand market&amp;hellip;).
This dashboard is built on Shiny and the R programming language (a proud New Zealand invention!).
Features Interactive map with dot size mapped to sales price, and dot colour mapped to &amp;ldquo;% over RV&amp;rdquo; Filter by neighbourhood Filter by property attributes like floor space or RV Browse tabular data for max.</description></item><item><title>Alexa Skill for New Zealand Earthquakes</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/alexa-skill-kiwi-quakes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/alexa-skill-kiwi-quakes/</guid><description>https://github.com/chillu/alexa-skill-kiwi-quakes
New Zealanders often ask themselves: Was that an earthquake, a truck going past, or just the wind? Now you can ask Alexa!
&amp;ldquo;Alexa, ask kiwi quakes if this was an earthquake&amp;rdquo;
Under the hood, it uses AWS Lambda functions deployed through the Serverless Framework.
I should acknowledge the awesome New Zealand GeoNet project and its sponsors EQC, GNS Science and LINZ, for providing data used in this app.</description></item><item><title>Echt: A social network based on face recognition</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/echt-face-recognition-social-network/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/echt-face-recognition-social-network/</guid><description>On Github: server and client
Worked with my good friend @bnolan to realise his idea for a minimalistic social network based on selfies and facial recognition. In short, you join by taking a photo, and you &amp;ldquo;friend&amp;rdquo; someone by taking a selfie with them. Being physically in the same space with the other person is a feature, not a bug. We&amp;rsquo;ve taken this idea to PoC stage and tested it with a few friends, before it lost steam.</description></item><item><title>Arduino Led Scarf</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/arduino-led-scarf/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/arduino-led-scarf/</guid><description>https://github.com/chillu/arduino-led-scarf
An art project was for Kiwiburn 2016 and 2017, the regional Burning Man in New Zealand. An Arduino Nano powers LEDs in a fully scarf and stylish top hat, with buttons for mode controls. Comes with click-based beat matching and various &amp;ldquo;drop modes&amp;rdquo; for maximum awesomeness on electronic music. Got lots of advice on transistors from @sminnee and @stojg, and help in wrangling C from @bnolan.
This project taught me how to work within tiny compute constraints, and how unproductive coding in raw C can be!</description></item><item><title>Videovote: Simple video suggestion and voting app in Meteor and React</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/videovote/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/videovote/</guid><description>https://github.com/chillu/videovote
Allows users to suggest videos by pasting in their URLs. The app will automatically retrieve and list details on the video via the oEmbed protocol. By authenticating via Github, users can also vote on videos.
The use case for this app is company-internal &amp;ldquo;lunch and learn&amp;rdquo; sessions, where a group of devs get together to watch interesting conference talks. This was used in &amp;ldquo;production&amp;rdquo; at Silverstripe for a number of years.</description></item><item><title>Github Contribution Dashboard</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/github-dashing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/github-dashing/</guid><description>https://github.com/chillu/github-dashing
Dashboard to monitor the health of github projects based on their contribution statistics. Based on the Dashing framework (written in Ruby). This was used for a few years at the Silverstripe offices in Wellington, as an information radiator. In hindsight, the leaderboard surfaced some hidden heroes, but also incentivised less productive behaviours. The build dashboard was a game changer, given the extremely large amount of codebases supported by the teams it focused us on quality (or at least figuring out why builds are fragile&amp;hellip;).</description></item><item><title>Book: Silverstripe - The Complete Guide to CMS Development</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/silverstripe-book/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/silverstripe-book/</guid><description>Authored the first (paper!) book about Silverstripe CMS, with thousands of copies sold. The book was originally co-authored with Steven Broschart, and published in Germany for Galileo Computing.</description></item></channel></rss>