<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>chillu.com</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/</link><description>Recent content on chillu.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 16:26:05 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.chillu.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Analysing community health via Google BigQuery</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2021/telling-stories-with-data/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 16:26:05 +1200</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2021/telling-stories-with-data/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a steward for a reasonably large open source community (Silverstripe CMS) for over a decade. My various roles working at the main sponsor of this community (Silverstripe Ltd) put me in a privileged position to talk to many awesome folks in this community, and influence the direction of the product. But along the way, I&amp;rsquo;ve also accumulated a lot of anecdotes, bias and gut feel about the &amp;ldquo;shape&amp;rdquo; of our community and its contributions.</description></item><item><title>Building a router table: Tool recursion in the garage</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2021/router-table/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 16:26:05 +1200</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2021/router-table/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a good rabbit hole for you:
How do you make nice looking furniture? You add crisp insets and bevels. How do you add those to furniture stock? You get a handheld router. How do you do that precisely? You mount the router upside down into a table. How do you build that table? You design it in 3D. How do you mount that router in the table? You buy an aluminium insert plate.</description></item><item><title>A tale of servers and clients: Auth and rendering with NextJS, Auth0 and Hasura</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2021/tale-of-server-client-auth0-hasura/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 16:26:05 +1200</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2021/tale-of-server-client-auth0-hasura/</guid><description>The best and worst aspect of web development is that approaches change reasonably often, and sometimes even for the better! I&amp;rsquo;m catching up on some of these trends:
Hybrid rendering: Blurring the lines between client and server with SSR and hydrated state Identity as a service: Handling authentication and authorisation through third party delegation Serverless: Isolated (often stateless) compute on managed infrastructure with great scalability promises Live views: Applications subscribe to data updates rather than waiting for page refreshes GraphQL: Strongly typed APIs with smart servers and clients They all deserve their own posts.</description></item><item><title>New website ... again!</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2021/new-website-again/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 16:26:05 +1200</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2021/new-website-again/</guid><description>In the great tradition of my people (developers), I have taken to rebuilding my personal website, again. Apart from building your own CMS, this appears to be a rite of passage at least for my generation. It&amp;rsquo;s on Hugo now, a blazingly fast system built on Golang. Hey, at least I didn&amp;rsquo;t put it on a Kubernetes cluster! To celebrate the occasion, I&amp;rsquo;m looking back the tools I&amp;rsquo;ve used over the years.</description></item><item><title>Silverstripe CMS: Where is 5.x, or how to innovate on a monolith</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2021/silverstripe-where-is-5x/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2021/silverstripe-where-is-5x/</guid><description>Originally posted on silverstripe.org
At Silverstripe Ltd, we&amp;rsquo;ve been mapping out how we can help developers innovate around Silverstripe CMS. Coordinating with the Silverstripe CMS Core Committers, we wanted to bring you an update on Silverstripe CMS and its future. We see the CMS as a platform for innovation with a lean and modular core, leaving opportunities for the ecosystem to thrive on those foundations while keeping CMS 4.x projects sustainable long-term.</description></item><item><title>Contributions to Silverstripe CMS</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/silverstripe/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/silverstripe/</guid><description>Contributed nearly a thousand pull requests and collaborated with hundreds of community members on the many repos making up Silverstripe CMS (PHP and Javascript) since 2005 until today. Silverstripe is a product of over a hundred individual repos, and my contributions are scattered among them (see my github.com/silverstripe contribution timeline).
There were a few major areas of focus over the years for myself, with the help of many open source contributors:</description></item><item><title>Talk: StripeCon 2020 - Github Issue Relevancy Predictions</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2020/talk-stripecon-2020/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2020/talk-stripecon-2020/</guid><description>Machine learning experiment, creating personalised predictions using Fast.AI, Pytorch, Pandas, Flask (Python).
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ujv2kkmaTLE</description></item><item><title>Supporting you in dependency vulnerability checks</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2020/dependency-vulnerability-checks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2020/dependency-vulnerability-checks/</guid><description>Originally posted on silverstripe.org
Silverstripe CMS supports developers in secure coding practices and website owners in running secure websites and applications. A big part of this is rigour around security releases of our supported modules and communicating the impact of any vulnerabilities found there (see last year’s blog post: A better security classification for supported modules). But any website with our CMS will also pull in community modules as well as other dependencies not managed by us and dependencies which aren’t even in the PHP ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Panel Discussion: Headless, GraphQL and Content First (Stripecon EU)</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2020/discussion-headless-stripecon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2020/discussion-headless-stripecon/</guid><description>Facilitated an interesting discussion with the Silverstripe community around the role of Headless in Silverstripe&amp;rsquo;s current and future usage. See recording</description></item><item><title>Personalised predictions of issue relevancy through machine learning</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/github-issue-ml-relevancy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/github-issue-ml-relevancy/</guid><description>https://github.com/chillu/github-issue-ml-relevancy
Too many Github notifications, too little time. The obvious answer there is to spend lots of time creating a hyper personalised prediction engine that can tell me what I&amp;rsquo;m interested in. And learn a whole bunch of stuff on the way. This is a tongue-in-cheek experiment, which resulted in a realisation that I&amp;rsquo;m pretty unpredictable.
See it in action (predictions for the chillu github user):
http://github-issue-ml-relevancy.herokuapp.com
What does this do?</description></item><item><title>New CMS demo for a better evaluator experience</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2019/new-cms-demo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2019/new-cms-demo/</guid><description>Originally posted on silverstripe.org. I&amp;rsquo;ve been the Product Owner and Technical Lead on this project.
Silverstripe CMS offers a flexible solution for your website or application. Its open source and modular DNA provides the best of both worlds for developers and CMS users, with a framework that can be easily adapted to suit your organisation’s needs, and an intuitive user interface that empowers teams to deliver great content. So you can easily evaluate what Silverstripe CMS offers, we’ve just launched a new demo that includes a robust set of features, providing a more comprehensive experience than the old open source demo.</description></item><item><title>A better security classification for supported modules</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2019/better-security-classification/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2019/better-security-classification/</guid><description>Originally posted on silverstripe.org
SilverStripe has published security releases for many years, with a well defined security release process. Each security issue we’ve identified was assigned an identifier, and a severity rating. Both of these were custom markers which we’ve applied based on our context. We’re adjusting this to be more in-line with large open source projects, which are depended on by thousands of organisations around the globe. We are also taking this opportunity to redefine how security fixes are handled in “Limited Support” release lines such as SilverStripe 3.</description></item><item><title>Github Issue Tracker</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/silverstripe-issue-tracker/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/silverstripe-issue-tracker/</guid><description>VueJS frontend to aggregate Github issues through their GraphQL API, deployed on Vercel</description></item><item><title>Property Trends Analysis Dashboard</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/property-trends-dashboard/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/property-trends-dashboard/</guid><description>https://github.com/chillu/property-viewer-shiny-dashboard
Applied data analysis to my own house hunting back in 2018. I choose to believe this was a factor in not over-paying for the house we bought (if that is even possible in the New Zealand market&amp;hellip;).
This dashboard is built on Shiny and the R programming language (a proud New Zealand invention!).
Features Interactive map with dot size mapped to sales price, and dot colour mapped to &amp;ldquo;% over RV&amp;rdquo; Filter by neighbourhood Filter by property attributes like floor space or RV Browse tabular data for max.</description></item><item><title>Headless CMS: The future of content delivery</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2018/future-of-content-delivery/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2018/future-of-content-delivery/</guid><description>Originally posted on silverstripe.org
When we talk about the future of content delivery, we’re interested with how content and data will be published on websites and what advances in web technologies will make this more effective for teams. We introduced a few of these concepts as part of a recent meetup for the Common Web Platform (CWP) community. SilverStripe Solution Architect Ingo Schommer previously covered headless CMS in a great technical overview, this post however looks at the same topic but how it relates to marketers and content teams.</description></item><item><title>Alexa Skill for New Zealand Earthquakes</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/alexa-skill-kiwi-quakes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/alexa-skill-kiwi-quakes/</guid><description>https://github.com/chillu/alexa-skill-kiwi-quakes
New Zealanders often ask themselves: Was that an earthquake, a truck going past, or just the wind? Now you can ask Alexa!
&amp;ldquo;Alexa, ask kiwi quakes if this was an earthquake&amp;rdquo;
Under the hood, it uses AWS Lambda functions deployed through the Serverless Framework.
I should acknowledge the awesome New Zealand GeoNet project and its sponsors EQC, GNS Science and LINZ, for providing data used in this app.</description></item><item><title>Echt: A social network based on face recognition</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/echt-face-recognition-social-network/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/echt-face-recognition-social-network/</guid><description>On Github: server and client
Worked with my good friend @bnolan to realise his idea for a minimalistic social network based on selfies and facial recognition. In short, you join by taking a photo, and you &amp;ldquo;friend&amp;rdquo; someone by taking a selfie with them. Being physically in the same space with the other person is a feature, not a bug. We&amp;rsquo;ve taken this idea to PoC stage and tested it with a few friends, before it lost steam.</description></item><item><title>Talk: GraphQL in SilverStripe - Reasons and Demo App (Stripecon Malta 2017)</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2017/talk-stripecon-eu-2017/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2017/talk-stripecon-eu-2017/</guid><description>Talk at Stripecon Malta in 2017. I&amp;rsquo;ve built a PoC, demonstrating the new GraphQL module exposing Silverstripe CMS data through a simple app built on React Apollo, and deployed on Zeit (which has been rebranded to Vercel).
See slides and talk recording.</description></item><item><title>Talk: Silverstripe 4 Technical Roadmap (Stripecon Malta 2017)</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2017/talk-silverstripe4-technical-roadmap/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2017/talk-silverstripe4-technical-roadmap/</guid><description>Technical roadmap talk at Stripecon Malta in 2017, focused on what&amp;rsquo;s coming up in Silverstripe 4.
See slides and talk recording.</description></item><item><title>Talk: Fitting GraphQL into a CMS data model (Wellington PHP Meetup 2017)</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2017/talk-fitting-graphql-in-a-cms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2017/talk-fitting-graphql-in-a-cms/</guid><description>Lightning talk for the Wellington PHP Meetup, about the challenges of matching an ActiveRecord style ORM in a PHP-based CMS with GraphQL&amp;rsquo;s type language.
See slides.</description></item><item><title>Arduino Led Scarf</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/arduino-led-scarf/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/arduino-led-scarf/</guid><description>https://github.com/chillu/arduino-led-scarf
An art project was for Kiwiburn 2016 and 2017, the regional Burning Man in New Zealand. An Arduino Nano powers LEDs in a fully scarf and stylish top hat, with buttons for mode controls. Comes with click-based beat matching and various &amp;ldquo;drop modes&amp;rdquo; for maximum awesomeness on electronic music. Got lots of advice on transistors from @sminnee and @stojg, and help in wrangling C from @bnolan.
This project taught me how to work within tiny compute constraints, and how unproductive coding in raw C can be!</description></item><item><title>Talk: React and Asset Abstraction in Silverstripe 4 (Silverstripe Meetup)</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2016/talk-react-and-assets-in-silverstripe4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2016/talk-react-and-assets-in-silverstripe4/</guid><description>Roadmap update on the CMS UI redesign, React refactor and asset management overhaul in Silverstripe 4. See slides</description></item><item><title>Talk: Silverstripe 4 Roadmap Update (Stripecon APAC in Sydney)</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2016/talk-silverstripe-roadmap-stripecon-apac/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2016/talk-silverstripe-roadmap-stripecon-apac/</guid><description>Roadmap update at our first conference in Australia, see slides.</description></item><item><title>Videovote: Simple video suggestion and voting app in Meteor and React</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/videovote/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/videovote/</guid><description>https://github.com/chillu/videovote
Allows users to suggest videos by pasting in their URLs. The app will automatically retrieve and list details on the video via the oEmbed protocol. By authenticating via Github, users can also vote on videos.
The use case for this app is company-internal &amp;ldquo;lunch and learn&amp;rdquo; sessions, where a group of devs get together to watch interesting conference talks. This was used in &amp;ldquo;production&amp;rdquo; at Silverstripe for a number of years.</description></item><item><title>Github Contribution Dashboard</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/github-dashing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/github-dashing/</guid><description>https://github.com/chillu/github-dashing
Dashboard to monitor the health of github projects based on their contribution statistics. Based on the Dashing framework (written in Ruby). This was used for a few years at the Silverstripe offices in Wellington, as an information radiator. In hindsight, the leaderboard surfaced some hidden heroes, but also incentivised less productive behaviours. The build dashboard was a game changer, given the extremely large amount of codebases supported by the teams it focused us on quality (or at least figuring out why builds are fragile&amp;hellip;).</description></item><item><title>Behat Step Transformations for Relative Time</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2013/2013-11-15-behat-step-transformations-for-relative-time-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 13:54:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2013/2013-11-15-behat-step-transformations-for-relative-time-2/</guid><description>class MyFeatureContext extends BehatContext {
protected $dateFormat = 'Y-m-d'; /** * Transforms relative date statements compatible with strtotime(). * Example: &amp;quot;date 2 days ago&amp;quot; might return &amp;quot;2013-10-10&amp;quot; if its currently * the 12th of October 2013. Customize through {@link setDateFormat()}. * * @Transform /^(?:(the|a)) date of (?.*)$/ */ public function castRelativeToAbsoluteDate($prefix, $val) { $timestamp = strtotime($val); if(!$timestamp) { throw new \InvalidArgumentException(sprintf( &amp;quot;Can't resolve '%s' into a valid datetime value&amp;quot;, $val )); } return date($this-&amp;amp;gt;dateFormat, $timestamp); } public function getDateFormat() { return $this-&amp;amp;gt;dateFormat; } public function setDateFormat($format) { $this-&amp;amp;gt;dateFormat = $format; } }</description></item><item><title>DIY work setup: A combined sitting and standing desk</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2013/2013-02-16-diy-work-setup-a-combined-sitting-and-standing-desk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2013 19:44:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2013/2013-02-16-diy-work-setup-a-combined-sitting-and-standing-desk/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a sloucher with terrible posture, and I would like to keep working in my sedentary profession of a programmer for quite a while. Current research suggests that sitting all day isn&amp;rsquo;t good for you (nytimes.com). Standing all day isn&amp;rsquo;t ideal either. I&amp;rsquo;m also a passionate DIYer. So I set out and built myself a standing and sitting desk, combining the best of both worlds.
Disclaimer: I&amp;rsquo;m not studied in ergonomics, and just documenting a setup which has worked for me for about half a year now.</description></item><item><title>Indoor gardening with a window farm</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2012/2012-04-22-photo-post/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2012 19:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2012/2012-04-22-photo-post/</guid><description>After being inspired by a TED talk about window farms, I decided to build my own! I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a tinkerer, and like greens around me. One day I&amp;rsquo;ll have an awesome veggie garden, but for now a window farm is the best option for our small city apartment. So why not just put plants on the window sill? Its just more space saving with a window farm, as you use less room for containers through hydroponics and efficient continuous watering.</description></item><item><title>A New Home</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2010/2010-06-29-a-new-home/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2010 21:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2010/2010-06-29-a-new-home/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Link post</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2010/2010-06-29-link-post/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2010 13:36:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2010/2010-06-29-link-post/</guid><description>http://vimeo.com/12819723
Short film by Michael Koerbel, shot and edited entirely on an iPhone 4. Someone apparently forgot to send him the memo that iOS devices are only for consumption, not creation.
★</description></item><item><title>Book: Silverstripe - The Complete Guide to CMS Development</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/silverstripe-book/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/silverstripe-book/</guid><description>Authored the first (paper!) book about Silverstripe CMS, with thousands of copies sold. The book was originally co-authored with Steven Broschart, and published in Germany for Galileo Computing.</description></item><item><title>Raaaandom!</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2007/2007-11-25-raaaandom/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2007 18:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2007/2007-11-25-raaaandom/</guid><description>Randomness #1: Turns out we were (involuntarily) following the traces of Sigourney Weaver last weekend, who happened to be at the Mighty Mighty and “Lanes”-bowling wednesday and thursday (we went friday and saturday) – see article in the Dominion Post. From now on, I’ll stalk celebrities with web 2.0 power: The local mapping service “Zoomin” actually has a Wellington Celeb Vista group which maps celebrity sightings haha.
Randomness #2: I could’ve sworn I’ve seen Reiner, an ex-workmate from german Scholz &amp;amp; Volkmer the other day at J.</description></item><item><title>Hills, maps, sun &amp; coffee</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2007/2007-11-24-hills-maps-sun-coffee/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2007 21:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2007/2007-11-24-hills-maps-sun-coffee/</guid><description>A quick uncoherent summary of what I’m up to down under: Last week I met Diana, an ex-workmate from good ol’ Scholz &amp;amp; Volkmer. She’s travelling through Ozzie and NZ with her friend Madleen, and had a two-day stop in Wellington. We didn’t manage to meet for over two years, so found it quite funny to sip a coffee on the other end of the globe :)
Concerning work, I’m pretty much fulltime managing and developing for an US-based client doing a Google maps mashup, helping to get the awesome Silverstripe 2.</description></item><item><title>Sign language for beginners</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2007/2007-11-06-sign-language-for-beginners/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2007 20:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2007/2007-11-06-sign-language-for-beginners/</guid><description>One of the few practical side-effects about New Zealand being on the other end of the world is that you inevitably cross a whole lot of countries on your way. This meant that an “around-the-world” flight with several stopovers was only slightly more expensive than going to Wellington non-stop (1650€ vs 1400€). So there I was, virtually pointing the finger at my spinning globe in Google Earth, looking for interesting stopovers.</description></item><item><title>I'm about to produce 9t of CO2 emissions</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2007/2007-10-25-im-about-to-produce-9t-of-co2-emissions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2007 03:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2007/2007-10-25-im-about-to-produce-9t-of-co2-emissions/</guid><description>Leaving Germany next week for more exciting work at Silverstripe in New Zealand, I’m researching about my travel. With Web 2.0 and buzzword power of course.
At first i tried a web-app for planning my itinary: just send your flight-confirmation-emails to tripit, and they provide you with a nice printable travel-plan (with weather/maps/directions etc.). Unfortunately it didn’t accept the format of my booking agency, so no dice here (manual entry is way too tedious).</description></item><item><title>The €2 Laptop Stand</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2007/2007-10-03-the-2-laptop-stand/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2007 05:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2007/2007-10-03-the-2-laptop-stand/</guid><description>Update (04/10/2007): This article has been lifehacked. Thanks for all your comments!
Being a programmer, I crouch in front of computers a lot – obviously you want to avoid being a cripple with 30 and get an ergonomic workplace. Usually this means having a separately adjustable keyboard and screen in addition to my Macbook Pro. Currently i don’t have this luxury, so I came up with a really simple laptop stand to rise the screen-height and have a more relaxed wrist position.</description></item><item><title>JQuery columnizeList Plugin</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2007/2007-09-29-jquery-columnizelist-plugin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2007 13:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2007/2007-09-29-jquery-columnizelist-plugin/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a rainy german saturday hacking away on my dusty ol' website. Because of the current layout without sidebars, I had to find an unobtrusive place for meta-information like tags or archive-links. Those chunks of information can grow quite large, so i decided to expand into length rather than height and go multi-column for longer lists. Before I fully understood the stony way that lay before me, I&amp;rsquo;ve found an article on &amp;ldquo;A List Apart&amp;rdquo;-magazine outlining different ways to tackle this problem.</description></item><item><title>Outage - Teh PAIN!</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2007/2007-09-05-outage-teh-pain/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2007 12:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2007/2007-09-05-outage-teh-pain/</guid><description>Well, switching my blog to Mephisto was one thing, but taming a fastcgi-server on my shared-hosting-provider Site5 is a completely different story. Being the usual geek, I’ve applied way too much technology to a simple problem: Capistrano promises a solid automated deployment process, and is often used for Rails-based apps. Very interesting concept, and for more scientific than practical reasons I’ve spend nearly two days configuring this tool for chillu.com. Well, i’ve ended up 90% done, and an embarassing downtime while debugging fastcgi and mysterious rails-logs – sorry for that!</description></item><item><title>Running around naked</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2007/2007-08-16-running-around-naked/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2007 22:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2007/2007-08-16-running-around-naked/</guid><description>Remember the CSS Naked Day? I’m joining in a bit off schedule, and for slightly different reasons: After a bit of finetuning in March, I’m going style-naked as a way to force myself into an iterative redesign. Plans are to “publish early and often” and use chillu.com for fast prototyping in CSS, so expect some inconsistencies over the next weeks. I’ll document the process as its coming along, and looking forward to your feedback (yes, I’ve resurrected the commenting-system!</description></item><item><title>Disneyland with death penalty</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2007/2007-07-31-disneyland-with-death-penalty/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2007 22:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2007/2007-07-31-disneyland-with-death-penalty/</guid><description>On the way back to Germany I had a little “asia-preview” by staying in Singapore for two nights. As so often, the internet was very useful for figuring out to do in this timespan, and so I followed a wiki-based itinary from wikitravel.
Day 1 was dedicated to shopping on Orchard Street, a 2km-street with at least a dozen multi-storey shopping malls – it actually took me the better part of the day to walk through it.</description></item><item><title>Terra Australis Incognita</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2007/2007-07-31-terra-australis-incognita/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2007 09:09:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2007/2007-07-31-terra-australis-incognita/</guid><description>Time flies, especially with a fun job in an awesome city on the other end of the globe. So the expiry of my Work&amp;amp;Travel visa advanced quickly, and the inevitable flight back to Germany proved a good opportunity for a holiday. I always wondered why people would live in such a crazy continent as Australia, so the goal was obvious – three weeks of sun, beaches and dangerous animals on the east coast.</description></item><item><title>Tasty flowers</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2007/2007-03-10-tasty-flowers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2007 10:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2007/2007-03-10-tasty-flowers/</guid><description>After all the talk about “the real life” on my blog, it is clearly time for a geeky post ;) Today I’m moving another part of my digital life online: Bookmarks. I’m probably a bit late to the party here, but I evaluated the options for quite a while. I wasn’t too impressed with the feature-set and user interface of deli.cio.us (besides the fact that I can never remember where to put those damn dots…).</description></item><item><title>Wodyauptu</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2007/2007-01-17-wodyauptu/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2007 22:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2007/2007-01-17-wodyauptu/</guid><description>&amp;hellip; eine typische Kiwi-Begrüßung, heißt in etwa “Wie gehts, was machst du so?” (“What are you up to?”) – und genau das will ich heute mal bloggen, es gibt genug zu erzählen.
Ich hab endlich meinen Arsch hochgekriegt und bin aus meinem öden Einzelzimmer in eine WG gezogen. Mein “mate” Ben geht für ein paar Monate nach Deutschland, und was läge da näher als sein Zimmer an nen Deutschen nachzuvermieten? Außerdem wohnen hier noch zwei Jungs von SilverStripe, passt also wunderbar.</description></item><item><title>"Sommerurlaub" im Herr-der-Ringe-Land</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2007/2007-01-06-sommerurlaub-im-herr-der-ringe-land/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2007 11:42:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2007/2007-01-06-sommerurlaub-im-herr-der-ringe-land/</guid><description>Weihnachtszeit ist Familienzeit – sogar für temporäre Auswanderer wie mich: Meine Eltern und meine kleine Schwester Karolin haben Geschenke und Sonnenbrille eingepackt, um mich für einen kurzen Sommerurlaub auf der Südhalbkugel zu besuchen – vielen Dank fürs Vorbeikommen!
Erste Erkenntnis: Wellington ist über die Feiertage eine Geisterstadt, wir haben am ersten Weihnachtsfeiertag genau ein offenes Restaurant in der kompletten Innenstadt gefunden (die meisten sind geschlossen, um sich vor den horrenden Feiertagsgehältern zu drücken, und Kiwis kochen über Weihnachten anscheinend lieber selbst).</description></item><item><title>Gummiseile, Hügel, und viele Schafe</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2006/2006-10-30-gummiseile-hgel-und-viele-schafe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2006 21:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2006/2006-10-30-gummiseile-hgel-und-viele-schafe/</guid><description>Eigentlich war ich ja noch garnicht richtig in Neuseeland – ich bin in Wellington gelandet, und seitdem eigentlich nur auf Bürgersteigen, in Büroräumen und Kneipen rumgerannt. Da mussten schon zwei Deutsche herfliegen, um mich aus meinem Kiwi-Alltag in die grünen Weiten der Nordinsel zu zerren. Und so habe ich meine Schwester Mona und ihren Freund Carsten letzte Woche von der Fähre abgeholt, voll bepackt für einen 10-tägigen Trip. Die beiden waren froh, endlich wieder in einer Stadt zu sein, die nicht um zehn abends alle Bürgersteige hochklappt (ohne Witz, neuseeländische “Städte” sind erschreckend…unbevölkert, vor allem in der Nebensaison).</description></item><item><title>Wellingtonian</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2006/2006-08-23-wellingtonian/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2006 22:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2006/2006-08-23-wellingtonian/</guid><description>Nach drei Wochen Neuseeland bin ich jetzt wohl richtig “angekommen” – ich gehe inzwischen auch auf dem Bürgersteig links, zahle jeden Cent-Betrag mit Geldkarte und erschrecke mich nicht mehr, wenn neben mir die Sirene einer Fußgängerampel losgeht – wie ein normaler Kiwi eben. Dem deutschen Hochsommer brauche ich ja auch nicht nachtrauern, da dieser pünktlich mit meiner Abreise aufgehört hat und wir jetzt fast identischen Temparaturen haben. Eine größere Umstellung ist die Ernährung: Sweet-Chili-Soße auf dem Döner, “Meat Pies” (Blätterteig-Kuchen mit Fleischfüllung) und “Brot” (man beachte die Anführungszeichen: für den Durchschnittsdeutschen ist hier sogar das gute “Bürger-Bread” nur labbriges Toast ohne jeden Nährwert).</description></item><item><title>Antipode</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2006/2006-08-06-antipode/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2006 17:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2006/2006-08-06-antipode/</guid><description>Es hat alles angefangen (oder aufgehört?) mit einer gelungenen Abschiedsparty in der Römer-WG (die ich schon jetzt sehr vermisse…) – mit Vodka-Calippo, Gummiboot-Hüten und Rabarber-Schlachten (Fotos gibts auf Flickr. Aber non-public, da wohl zu peinlich… also bitte tragt euch als meine Buddies ein).
Und nachdem ich dachte, ich hätte den schweren Teil des Abschieds schon hinter mir, laufen die mir doch noch bis zum Flughafen hinterher und überraschen mich (nochmals vielen lieben Dank an Clemens, Melanie, Stefan, Daniel und Ingo R.</description></item><item><title>Bachelor and beyond</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2006/2006-08-06-bachelor-and-beyond/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2006 17:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2006/2006-08-06-bachelor-and-beyond/</guid><description>It probably took some days and about 20.000km of travel to realize: Wow, I’m really finished, and a new chapter in my life is about to start. I just graduated from University of Applied Sciences Darmstadt, after four years of studies. And after a lot of administrative chaos, I could now print “Bachelor of Arts (hons) in Media Production” on my oversized (non-existent) business cards.
In the meantime I spent three months hacking away on my pet-project and bachelor-thesis “Syndicure” – a web-based collaborative RSS-reader for info-junkies (more details on the developer weblog).</description></item><item><title>Sydney, 6Uhr morgens</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2006/2006-08-03-sydney-6uhr-morgens/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2006 08:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2006/2006-08-03-sydney-6uhr-morgens/</guid><description>Der größte Teil der Reise ist geschafft, soweit alles klar … noch einmal abheben und ich bin da :) Wo? Das erzähl ich dann nächstes Mal g</description></item><item><title>Insight: Apple-users are also better politicians</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2006/2006-05-26-insight-apple-users-are-also-better-politicians/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2006 05:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2006/2006-05-26-insight-apple-users-are-also-better-politicians/</guid><description>Do you still remember Al Gore? I just stumbled over a flaming pledge for environmental protection by this former vice-president of the U.S.. It’s not only a stunning example of a well-prepared presentation, but also contains very interesting insights by a man who nearly became head of the american administration – and even if he would talk more moderate if he actually won the election, there is still hope…
In fact the presentation was so good that somebody made a movie around it: An Inconvenient Truth (Trailer on apple.</description></item><item><title>GTD, finally</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2006/2006-03-22-gtd-finally/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2006 05:07:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2006/2006-03-22-gtd-finally/</guid><description>There are innumerous posts about getting things done (GTD), and I spent so much time reading them that I actually didn’t get anything done ;) So, what would a geek-blog be without it’s GTD-post – here’s my take on the topic: Organization of your life’s daily actions basically needs a consistent system. I tried really basic stuff such as moleskines (handwriting sucks) and text-files (too unflexible). Then I switched to Circusponies Notebook (no todo-categories), Backpack (online-only) and Burnoutmenu (clumsy UI).</description></item><item><title>Finetuning</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2006/2006-03-15-finetuning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2006 12:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2006/2006-03-15-finetuning/</guid><description>Trying to develop after the open-source-principle “Publish early and often” I’m releasing some “under the hood”-updates to this website. A new design is on the way, but for today the focus is on content and functionality. I’m very inspired by the fresh ideas of signal vs. noise, the weblog by Ruby-on-Rails-creator 37signals – especially one post titled “A challenge for 2006: Cut your site in half”. So, what’s been done:</description></item><item><title>Die gute alte Piemont-Kirsche</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2006/2006-02-16-die-gute-alte-piemont-kirsche/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2006 20:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2006/2006-02-16-die-gute-alte-piemont-kirsche/</guid><description>Das Magazin Brand Eins fragt sich: “Wo ist eigentlich Piemont?”, in Anlehung an die unsäglichen TV-Spots der Firma Ferrero. Mein Recherchewunsch für’s nächste Mal: Wer macht eigentlich die Werbung für Kinder Pingui – und kann man sowas nicht irgendwie verbieten? Gefunden über Verge, blogged, den Agenturblog von Ogilvy Verge – auch sehr fein.</description></item><item><title>Doing stuff with images and colors</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2006/2006-02-06-doing-stuff-with-images-and-colors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2006 08:09:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2006/2006-02-06-doing-stuff-with-images-and-colors/</guid><description>Yay, my first OSX-application is ready: “ColorThing” – the outcome of the “Interactive Ccocoa”-course in my current studies. The (very creative) title signifies an evenly creative and complex task: Getting some average colors out of multiple source-images and … well, save them (into Photoshop-palettes). I know, it probably won’t be the next Delicious Library, but I sure had a lot of fun doing the interface-design and working with all those cool OSX-technologies.</description></item><item><title>Koksen um die Mäuse zu vergessen</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2006/2006-02-06-koksen-um-die-muse-zu-vergessen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2006 03:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2006/2006-02-06-koksen-um-die-muse-zu-vergessen/</guid><description>Bin grade über den T-Shirt-Shop von Katz&amp;amp;Goldt gestolpert – sehr geil. Der Humor ist nicht jedermanns Sache, aber ich lach mich regelmäßig scheckig über die absolut trockenen und sinnbefreiten Statements. Max Goldt schreibt außerdem noch für die Titanic – sehr zu empfehlen: “Okay Mutter, ich mache die Aschenbechergymnastik in der Mittagsmaschine”, ein Buch mit den besten Kolumnen. Hier ein Beispiel der Comics und Fotos, die sich immer mal wieder darin finden – man verzeihe mir den schlechten Scan…</description></item><item><title>Blackboard-Odyssee</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-10-24-blackboard-odyssee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2005 01:56:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-10-24-blackboard-odyssee/</guid><description>Aus aktuellem Anlass mal eine kleine Geschichte aus dem allseits beliebten “Blackboard” – unserem offiziellen FH-Intranet-Tool – Vorsicht: langer und sinnloser Rant-Post: Ich bekomme in meinem RSS-Reader (vielen Dank an Simon und Ralf für die Implementierung!) eine Blackboard-News anzeigt: “Druckerei Dieburg” von Erika Fischer. Hm, Druckerei in Dieburg – wär ja mal was ganz neues – klick ich doch mal auf den “Course Link” (Seit wann hat Erika als Media-Sekretärin überhaupt einen “Course”?</description></item><item><title>Music-Listening 2.0</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-10-22-music-listening-20/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2005 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-10-22-music-listening-20/</guid><description>Our parents probably owned a dozen albums that carried them through their whole youth – nowadays, I’m already getting bored of the 4392 songs on my harddrive. I’m listening to the same music over and over again… Time for a fresh approach: Web-based collaborative listening! The free service “Last.fm” analyzes your musical taste by tracking iTunes (and for all you interface-masochists: It does WinAmp, too ;). Based on this data, Last.</description></item><item><title>- (void)readManual:(NSString)manual;</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-10-17-voidreadmanualnsstringmanual/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2005 21:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-10-17-voidreadmanualnsstringmanual/</guid><description>5kg Cocoa-Bücher mit 50g passender Schokolade: 99% Kakao! (Wie hält die überhaupt zusammen?)</description></item><item><title>Vorgartenmonster</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-10-17-vorgartenmonster/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2005 21:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-10-17-vorgartenmonster/</guid><description>Wieso krabbelt sowas überhaupt in meinem Garten rum? :D</description></item><item><title>Was Chillu mit Varnnavikaarangal zu tun hat</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-09-14-was-chillu-mit-varnnavikaarangal-zu-tun-hat/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2005 00:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-09-14-was-chillu-mit-varnnavikaarangal-zu-tun-hat/</guid><description>Grade die “Google Blogsearch” ausprobiert, eitel wie man so ist mit dem Suchbegriff “chillu”. Gut, paar Flickr-Photos, chillu.com zählt anscheinend nicht als “Blog” :) Aber dann ein doch etwas ungewöhnliches Ergebnis, das mir endlich die wahre Herkunft meines Nicknames aufzeigt! Kleiner Auszug: In section 4, Rachana establishes that chillu is not chillu. However, real issue is not with chillu. It is with chillu and chillu, because they are chillu and chillu, also respectively.</description></item><item><title>U.S.-Roundup (or how I learned to love american breakfast)</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-08-31-us-roundup-or-how-i-learned-to-love-american-breakfast/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2005 01:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-08-31-us-roundup-or-how-i-learned-to-love-american-breakfast/</guid><description>To keep me from falling asleep in mid-day due to jetlag, I’m compiling some words on my trip. This won’t be a lenghty day-by-day travel-story, I promise – just some things that come to my mind. For the record, I’ve been to: San Francisco, Zion National Park, Bryce Canyon, Laughlin, Las Vegas, Laughlin, Grand Canyon, Sedona, Los Angeles, Santa Maria, Santa Barbara, Carmel.
Nature At some places, you can randomly point your camera somewhere, and every shot seems like a postcard – nature in California and Nevada is rough, beautiful and always with a glazing blue sky.</description></item><item><title>Zwischenmeldung</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-08-26-zwischenmeldung/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2005 13:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-08-26-zwischenmeldung/</guid><description>Nur so zwischendurch…neue Bilder (RSS|Atom).</description></item><item><title>Sightseeing for Apple-Geeks</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-08-18-sightseeing-for-apple-geeks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2005 14:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-08-18-sightseeing-for-apple-geeks/</guid><description>So…what’s an Apple-Geeks first visit in SF? Apple-Store! Nice People, more iPods than actual Macs, a first look on the Mighty Mouse (which seems not so mighty at all…) – check my Flickr-Set!</description></item><item><title>California Dreamin'</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-08-18-california-dreamin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2005 14:53:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-08-18-california-dreamin/</guid><description>My Internship at Scholz &amp;amp; Volkmer is over since yesterday, and at the moment…we’ll, I’m in San Francisco! Two week trip with my family through the beautiful southwest of America – all documented here on chillu.com and my Flickr-Account – you might want to leave some comments there – as the comment-system in this blog is still fucked up… Stay tuned for more pics and reports! :)</description></item><item><title>Live ist doch immer noch am besten...</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-06-29-live-ist-doch-immer-noch-am-besten/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2005 05:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-06-29-live-ist-doch-immer-noch-am-besten/</guid><description>Jan hat die Woche in seinem neuem Weblog nach den besten Lauf-Liedern gefragt (“Jan rennt!). Gute Idee eigentlich, dieses gebloggte Musik-Sharing, besonders wenn sie persönlich kommentiert sind. In der “Neon” gibts so ne schöne Kolumne, in der Stars den kommentieren “Soundtrack meines Lebens” vorstellen – sowas mein ich. Ich suche heute nach den besten Live-Versionen aller Genres, und mach mal den Anfang:
Coldplay – Yellow (Live, 2003)
Geiles Live-Album Westernhagen – Freiheit (Live, Westfalenhalle/Dortmund)</description></item><item><title>My first Appearance on apple.de</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-06-28-my-first-appearance-on-applede/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2005 21:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-06-28-my-first-appearance-on-applede/</guid><description>Apple – Events – MacExpo 2005, 8th image. g Though I’d rather like to appear here, or here or here. Well, someday… :)</description></item><item><title>Copy kills ... errm, what exactly?</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-06-20-copy-kills-errm-what-exactly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2005 09:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-06-20-copy-kills-errm-what-exactly/</guid><description>Today I stumbled upon a nice comic about music-piracy and stuff – interesting and easy read. Another article that kept me nodding in acknowledgement was written by the CCC (Chaos Computer Club) some time ago. While the music industry is figuring out how to sustain their overblown distribution-channels, have a look at some free projects: Wired Mixter, London Booted and Mercedes Benz Mixed-Tape, which celebrates it’s 1st anniversary these days (and is done by Scholz &amp;amp; Volkmer, so it’s kinda self-promotion g).</description></item><item><title>RARRRR</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-06-05-rarrrr/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2005 23:56:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-06-05-rarrrr/</guid><description>Kleiner Braindump von “Rock am Ring” dieses Wochenende: Niemals neben pubertierenden Sachsen campen. Bei Marylin Manson lieber im Zelt bleiben. Bei Chemical Brothers Ohrenstöpsel mitnehmen…und ne Sonnenbrille, für die Lightshow. Bei Wir sind Helden und Silbermond über (endlich wieder) guten deutschen Rock/Pop freuen. Ein Bauzaunlieferant namens “Bekaert” hat unfreiwillig eine neue Religion gegründet. Jimny ist die neue Helga. Mehr als 2h schlafen, wenn man am nächsten Tag in die Agentur muss.</description></item><item><title>Mac-Metaphor</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-05-28-mac-metaphor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2005 23:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-05-28-mac-metaphor/</guid><description>Another (previously hardcore-windows) security expert, Winn Schwartau, switched to Mac. Someone seeing a trend here? ;) In his blog he argues about the switch, and unless many Apple-fanboys he’s got some straight-forward, unbiased facts – be sure to read his post “Mad As Hell: Metaphor 1.42”. Intro: “Once upon a time, in a world full of yucky bugs and evil burglars, there was a house named Windows, and it had many doors and many windows.</description></item><item><title>Worst Website ever</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-05-26-worst-website-ever/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2005 20:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-05-26-worst-website-ever/</guid><description>UI-Design deluxe. I mean, WHAT WERE THEY THINKING?! Note: This it NOT a Terminal-App, but a website open to the public….</description></item><item><title>Books (the analogue stuff with real paper...)</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-05-20-books-the-analogue-stuff-with-real-paper/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2005 07:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-05-20-books-the-analogue-stuff-with-real-paper/</guid><description>As you may know, I’m currently traveling about three hours a day to Wiesbaden where Scholz &amp;amp; Volkmer is located. It’s amazing how many stuff you’re able to read on such trips – my last “week-portion” was a whole year-volume of Wired Magazine! Same goes for books: I’m devouring them, and have become a regular at Amazon. Amongst others, there’s this one special book I’d like to share: A short history of nearly everything” by Bill Bryson.</description></item><item><title>Expanding my (non-existent) Blogroll</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-05-20-expanding-my-non-existent-blogroll/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2005 07:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-05-20-expanding-my-non-existent-blogroll/</guid><description>Two of my fellow Media-Production-colleagues started blogging: Ben Regali and Olaf Schülin. Olaf does his internship in Greece, so he should have a thing or two to blog about :) Another newcomer is Ingo Renner, my new room-mate over here in Dieburg. As a computer-science-student at FH Darmstadt he kinda fits nicely into our geek-house (and it’s just a matter of time to convert him to a mac-user *g*). We just have to figure out that name-duplication-thing…there can be only one true “Ingo” – huhuhaha :) BTW: I’m still waiting for www.</description></item><item><title>Japanese way of rocking Flash</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-05-05-japanese-way-of-rocking-flash/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2005 00:57:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-05-05-japanese-way-of-rocking-flash/</guid><description>Turn up your stereo (preferably with a bad-ass subwoofer), and enjoy one of the best Flash-animations I’ve ever seen. It’s called Tokyoplastic, a design-group from Japan. These guys really know their 3D/Sound-Tools, and created a very unique style. Be sure to check out their newest sub-website as well: Tokyoplastic Music Box.</description></item><item><title>My Info-Addiction</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-04-27-my-info-addiction/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2005 08:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-04-27-my-info-addiction/</guid><description>Check out my Bloglines-Account to see what I’m talking about: More than 50 news-sources generate about 200-300 news-items for me every day. Gee, great! While it’s nice to have all those webdesign-trends, music-reviews and mac-rumors in one place, it’s getting a real burden to keep up to the masses of information. I’ve even begun to relay news-item into bookmarks for “later reading” rather than simply dismissing them. While some of the information is valueable for my job/studies, most of it is just gossip and pointless info-junk.</description></item><item><title>Frustrator</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-04-18-frustrator/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2005 07:44:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-04-18-frustrator/</guid><description>I guess I have to delete one entry from my previous wanna-work-list – Adobe just bought Macromedia! Now one of the most innovative and web-focused companies around is owned by a print-gigant failing to be a web-company for years. GREAT! I always respected Macromedia for not misusing their monopol in Flash-Technology, staying in close contact with its users and developers, and always astonishing us with new advances (AS2, FlashPaper, 8Ball). I guess these times are over.</description></item><item><title>Den Tiger im Tank</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-04-13-den-tiger-im-tank/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2005 08:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-04-13-den-tiger-im-tank/</guid><description>Mein Powerbook is zwar weg (doch kaputt, grml), dafür is der Tiger bald da. Und is auch schon im Familypack bestellt, jipee! Hier ein paar meiner persönlichen Highlights (Original nur in Englisch verfügbar, aber schnell mal deutsch kommentiert):
Adressbook: Contact Import File Formats (wurde auch mal Zeit…) Adressbook: Pocket Address Book Printing (super-praktisch!) iChat: Bluetooth Headset Support (endlich ein Einsatzzweck *g*) iChat: Grouping (Proteus adé?) Finder Slideshow (unbedingt Preview gucken!</description></item><item><title>Just another Google Link</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-04-05-just-another-google-link/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2005 21:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-04-05-just-another-google-link/</guid><description>I didn’t test Google Maps because somehow it didn’t show up on Firefox/Mac, but heard a lot about it. And guess what? They did Google Satellite! You can zoom into the whole USA with such a level of photographic detail, I’m blown away…you can literally drag yourself from Manhattan to Sunset Blvd. in seconds! Go Google! BTW: Did you know Google-Employees are allowed to work 20% of their time on personal projects, which may be published via Google Labs?</description></item><item><title>Rrrrrrrrrr...Resurrection</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-04-04-rrrrrrrrrrresurrection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2005 06:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-04-04-rrrrrrrrrrresurrection/</guid><description>Somehow the mac-gods seem to like me: My powerbook works again! Well, &amp;hellip; after some volume-repairing and S.M.A.R.T.-checking the drive booted again. Though it still makes some awkward noises now and then, it seems to function perfectly. My relationship and trust to my Powerbook is seriously damaged, though ;D</description></item><item><title>Krrrt-Krrrt-Tack-Tack</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-04-02-krrrt-krrrt-tack-tack/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2005 09:27:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-04-02-krrrt-krrrt-tack-tack/</guid><description>The sound of a dying harddrive – more frightening to every computer-user than any horror-movie. Today my 11-month-old Powerbook-drive died without prior warning-signs, just like that. Thanks to Super Duper I have a week-old backup of my whole drive, which boots nicely on my machine (OSX rocks!). But nevertheless, I’ll have to get this fixed – which means 1-2 weeks without my machine. In study-times this would be hell, but hey…due to my internship I have no time to use it at all.</description></item><item><title>Problemlösungs-Strategien in der Römer-WG</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-04-02-problemlsungs-strategien-in-der-rmer-wg/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2005 02:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-04-02-problemlsungs-strategien-in-der-rmer-wg/</guid><description>(ohne Worte…g)</description></item><item><title>SXSW</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-03-21-sxsw/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2005 08:58:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-03-21-sxsw/</guid><description>The SXSW-Webdeveloper-Conference 2005 (sxsw.org) has closed a couple of days ago. Man, I would LOVE to be there one day – if it wasn’t for the trip to Austin/TX ;) But for everybody who missed Zeldman, Meyer, Tantek, Hicks and the like, there’s some transcripts and slides out there at NewPRWiki. I guess the really cutting-edge-days of SXSW are over, but nethertheless there are some interesting topics to read. P.S.: Hello GoogleBot, please follow the above links for your pleasure…and my pagerank g.</description></item><item><title>Am I addicted?</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-03-20-am-i-addicted/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2005 02:44:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-03-20-am-i-addicted/</guid><description>I’m just buying my sixth and seventh shirt from threadless.com. I don’t know if it’s just the first rays of sun in Germany, or my addiction to shirts in general. But hey, they’re so darned cheap (10$ each)! :D Plus, I can now get my daily fix of well-designed and meaningful clothing at “preshrunk, a weblog dedicated only to shirt-stuff.</description></item><item><title>Ähh, wie hieß das nochmal auf Englisch...</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-03-16-hh-wie-hie-das-nochmal-auf-englisch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2005 08:44:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-03-16-hh-wie-hie-das-nochmal-auf-englisch/</guid><description>So, heute ist Blog-Tag…viel zu schreiben, wenig Zeit. Und immer mit dabei der alte Konflikt zwischen weltoffener englisch-sprachiger Präsenz und dem leichten Schreibfluß der Muttersprache (in meinem Fall: deutsch). Ich habe mich entschlossen, zukünftig in deutsch ODER englisch zu bloggen, frei nach dem Vorbild von Thomas und Eva. Im Optimalfall wird fein säuberlich getrennt zwischen Projekt-News/Announcements auf englisch, und schnell dahingesauten Linktipps auf deutsch (da fängts schon an, wie würde ich “dahingesaut” auf Englisch schreiben?</description></item><item><title>OMG-3D-VID</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-03-16-omg-3d-vid/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2005 08:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-03-16-omg-3d-vid/</guid><description>Today I’ve stumbled across this wonderfully thoughtful and perfectly crafted 3d-short named “Delivery”. One of the best student-3d-films I’ve ever seen – I’ve watched it three times until now: one run for story, one for textures and one for rendering ;) And the most stunning: It was made by a media-student over at FH Mainz, as a diploma-work, ALONE!</description></item><item><title>Warning: Dangerous Links included</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-03-06-warning-dangerous-links-included/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2005 05:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-03-06-warning-dangerous-links-included/</guid><description>Surfing around on a lazy sunday, I found a couple of links I’d like to share with you guys. Well, they’re dangerous at least if you’re a webdesigner like me who keeps thinking “Why didn’t I do this myself?!” ;).
http://www.matthewmahon.com/
http://www.motionblur.no/film.php?page=commercials
http://www.matthewmahon.com/
Most links are from the new issue of Wellvetted.</description></item><item><title>Winter Wonderland</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-02-21-winter-wonderland/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2005 01:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-02-21-winter-wonderland/</guid><description>In the bit of free time between university and the start of my internship I’m recovering at home, in good ol’ Hunsrück. And as the photo shows, we’re quite snowed in! I love snow, and it’s a shame nobody wants to help me building a snowman… :D</description></item><item><title>Studies, Internship, (Life)</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-02-08-studies-internship-life/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2005 22:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-02-08-studies-internship-life/</guid><description>As a result of the last few months (with rare blog-entries), I proudfully present three new projects: Kleidermarkt.de, Mediamap and the short animation “Sport ist Mord”. Two of them are produced with Typo3, a fact that somehow bothers me as I feel cornered as a “Typo3-Developer”. Perhaps I should do some concept- and design-work again… The last project is done with Maya, a tool that fascinates me time and again. But in the end 3D-animation is only a hobby, as I don’t consider myself an “3d-expert”.</description></item><item><title>One more thing...</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-01-24-one-more-thing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2005 20:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-01-24-one-more-thing/</guid><description>Hey, look what the postman delivered today :D White earbuds finally!</description></item><item><title>VIVA-Dejavú</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-01-02-viva-dejav/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2005 06:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2005/2005-01-02-viva-dejav/</guid><description>One more reason to completely dump television: “Fast Forward” is discontinued! Tonight at 23:00 Charlotte Roche will make her last appearance on the legendary music-show. No more interesting newcomers, no more funny interviews – just for the sake of selling more ringtones to stupid kids… If you were lucky enough to have “Eutelsat” or cable some years ago, you probably know VIVA2 – the predecessor of Viva Plus. “Fast Forward” is one of the few remainders of it’s very innovative and interesting programme (Zelluloid, ZwoBot, 2Rock, hmmm).</description></item><item><title>Kickin' Christmas</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-12-26-kickin-christmas/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2004 01:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-12-26-kickin-christmas/</guid><description>Merry Xmas! Hope you all got through these days without big family-desasters :) In my case all went smoothly, in fact we battled each other only on my mum’s brand-new super-duper Kicker (in english its “Foosball” – strange translation…). Hm, perhaps I should return home again ;) By the way: This may be your 25th last christmas. The NASA Near Earth Object Program discovered “2004 MN4”, which has a 1/62-chance of hitting the earth on in 2029 (on a Friday 13th!</description></item><item><title>Comments!</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-12-19-comments/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2004 01:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-12-19-comments/</guid><description>Whohooo, I’ve finally got a working commenting-system for my weblog! It wasn’t easy, and still isn’t perfect, but hey – you can type in letters which somehow appear on my webpage…good start. Some boring details: Typo3-wise this is a merge of tt_news and chc_forum, a rather crazy combination (putting up a whole forum-system for simple comments), and needed lots of template-rewriting (Thanks to Rupert Germann for his excellent extension). Feel free to comment on new posts, and if you still remember something on old posts – go ahead, I’m happy about every comment :)</description></item><item><title>I don't like US-Hiphop but...</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-12-14-i-dont-like-us-hiphop-but/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2004 10:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-12-14-i-dont-like-us-hiphop-but/</guid><description>&amp;hellip;this compilation really got onto my iTunes-Hotlist: “Jay-Z vs. The Beatles – The Grey Album” – a unofficial bootleg-album by DJ Dangermouse. You may download it at textz.com, although it’s officially banned by EMI – but aren’t the best things in life for free? :) There’s also a background-feature at WIRED Magazine. Encore!</description></item><item><title>Best Blog-Entry ever</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-12-14-best-blog-entry-ever/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2004 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-12-14-best-blog-entry-ever/</guid><description>One of my definitive nominees is: “I would RTFM if there was as FM to FR” over at designbyfire. 100% ACK! I should write an article about Typo3, but just the other way round: “I would RTFM if there wasn’t 10.000 FMs to FR” g.</description></item><item><title>Firefox kommt (or: Finding a cheap way to get your name in the FAZ)</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-12-01-firefox-kommt-or-finding-a-cheap-way-to-get-your-name-in-the-faz/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 08:27:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-12-01-firefox-kommt-or-finding-a-cheap-way-to-get-your-name-in-the-faz/</guid><description>Look ma, I’m in the FAZ! At least in teeny tiny letters… FAZ means “Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung”, one of Germany’s biggest daily papers. The opensource-community uses this popularity by placing a full-page-ad in tomorrows edition about Firefox. Through donations on firefox-kommt.de of 10-40EUR per individual the team brought up about 50.000EUR with 2403 donators – enough for one page of FAZ. Hopefully my donation helped to spread the word – and convince a broad audience that there is a live beyond the dark side ;) In case you think that this is a very stupid reason to donate money to – I will also donate for “SOS Kinderdorf” this year to keep my good concience g OK, thats it for today…whew, what a media-appearance – I’m a celebrity ;)</description></item><item><title>Only 9:40min fame left</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-12-01-only-940min-fame-left/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 07:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-12-01-only-940min-fame-left/</guid><description>I’m on telly! This afternoon I was sitting unsuspectingly in our university-mensa when a TV-team approached our group. Normally I’m professional at hiding myself from attention, but this time Emerson shouted “Here, take Ingo!” (Todo: Come up with some payback for Emerson *g*). So I said my twopence about the mensa-situation (“1500 students vs. 200 chairs”), and was aired this evening on HR, a local tv-channel (see vid). Hm, ok – I’ve got another 9:40 minutes of fame left in average for my lifetime (if Andy Warhol is right), and I’m curious what I fill the rest with.</description></item><item><title>halflife halfdone</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-11-27-halflife-halfdone/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2004 00:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-11-27-halflife-halfdone/</guid><description>With about two years delay the probably most anticipated 3d-shooter is finally realeased: Halflife 2! &amp;hellip;And after another three days of downloading 3,5gb of game-data through Valve’s fantastic “error-try-later” Steam-service it also arrived at my computer. There are probably better game-reviewers than me, so I’ll keep it short: Wonderful graphics even on my ol’ Athlon1800 (+ Radeon9600XT), stunning physics (even the swings on a playground work as expected!). But whats most important: The gameplay is probably the best ever: Smart opponents, challenging and very diversified missions and great realistic atmosphere.</description></item><item><title>The Roomraiders-Effect</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-11-12-the-roomraiders-effect/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2004 06:27:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-11-12-the-roomraiders-effect/</guid><description>I’ve just watched MTV’s “Roomraiders” on telly, a dating-show where the candidates are judged by the condition and contents of their rooms. The thought popped up “What would they find in my room?” Well, a huge amount of technical gadgets, computer-literature, clothes lying around everywhere – thats about it. It’s not that I don’t listen to music, watch good films, collect family-photos – but everything is stored digitally in my Powerbook, invisible for any observer.</description></item><item><title>Jingle Bells *lala*</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-11-09-jingle-bells-lala/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2004 22:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-11-09-jingle-bells-lala/</guid><description>First snow in mid-November! :D Winter is here – and I’m on my way buying the third “Christstollen”-Cake for this year g</description></item><item><title>The perfect combination</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-11-08-the-perfect-combination/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2004 03:56:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-11-08-the-perfect-combination/</guid><description>Speaking of my WG-life: I’m was so damn lucky to get this room! Currently I’m bloggin this from my window-ledge with my wireless Powerbook, watching a beautyful clear sunset. At last germany isn’t this bad, in contrast to study in some strange countries with:
2000$-WGs (greets to Andi/Hawaii) Elektrotechnik-Studies (greets to Seb&amp;amp;Corny/Spain) Spiders and snakes (greets to Eva&amp;amp;Sepp/Australia) :)))</description></item><item><title>Verzettelt</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-11-07-verzettelt/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2004 04:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-11-07-verzettelt/</guid><description>Just returning from a WG-meeting with my flatmates – one of the rare occasions where all six inhabitants of this house are in one place. Well, at least five – our newest member, Bertrand, was missing (unentschuldigt! *g*). Apart from this meetings, we pracise a system of hearsay and notes – especially this week the whole house was cluttered with about ten notes about noisy door-banging, shopping-lists etc. My favorite one was a observation-map to define where all those fck*ng maggots (Maden) are coming from in the kitchen.</description></item><item><title>Mei inglisch is so german!</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-11-06-mei-inglisch-is-so-german/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2004 06:54:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-11-06-mei-inglisch-is-so-german/</guid><description>&amp;hellip;says Kerstin! She’s one of the few persons from school I actually stayed in contact with, mostly due to the fact that she’s as Instant-Messaging-addicted as my geeky self. Check out her blog at Livejournal, she’s a lovely person and has a very entertaining, right-into-the-face style of writing. OK, back to the bad-english-accusations: If I had a comment-system (something which is definetly on my long-term-todo-list) I would ask my readers…but lacking one, i just say: Yeah Kerstin, and your site is so…errrm…YELLOW!</description></item><item><title>Damn Weekends</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-11-06-damn-weekends/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2004 06:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-11-06-damn-weekends/</guid><description>Somehow I’ve lost the “weekend-feeling”. What used to be a time of relaxation, friends and fun is now a strange mixture of work and too-much-time-on-myself. This thursday (note: our weekend officially starts thursdays g) I didn’t go out with Xaver and some others to finish a deadline-dreading website instead. OK, no problem. But somehow I’ve even got a bad concience hanging out with TV and junk-food on a saturday, because there’s so much to do even at the beginning of this semester – I don’t wanna imagine how it’s end will like.</description></item><item><title>Political Playlists</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-11-02-political-playlists/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2004 22:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-11-02-political-playlists/</guid><description>Although the U.S.-Elections are not decided yet, the notion of “Four more Years” of war and lies with George W. Bush gives me a very sad feeling. My first reaction was to compile a playlist that expresses this. I’ve done the same thing shortly after the WTC-attacks. The Songs are (like the rest of my music-collection) a patchwork through centuries and genres:
R.E.M. – It’s The End Of The World Well, not quite – but it’s irony seems very fitting.</description></item><item><title>Helvetica R.I.P.++ &amp;&amp; IFR</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-10-20-helvetica-rip-ifr/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2004 05:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-10-20-helvetica-rip-ifr/</guid><description>I found it! ITC Officina Sans rocks my world! :D Other nice Sansserif-Fonts which complete the list in my post “Helvetica R.I.P.” below: Flora, Folio, Frutiger, Goudy Sans, Univers. In the post I also groaned on the lacking abilities to style fonts online: With a rather simple idea that lets you bang your head thinking “why didn’t I…” even this obstacle seems to be sovled. Shaun Inman presents the “Inman Flash Replacement (IFR)”-technique, which renders any given truetype-font inside a “flash-movie-header” dynamically.</description></item><item><title>Really Simple Syndi...what?</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-10-11-really-simple-syndiwhat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2004 17:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-10-11-really-simple-syndiwhat/</guid><description>RSS stands for “Really Simple Syndication”, which essentially means you can read content (mostly news and weblogs) off-site in a standardized format. chillu.com also joins the hype, and for the whole crowd who already subscribed to my feed (so, essentially macsepp g), I’ve got a new feed-url. There are lots of applications out there for reading those “RSS-feeds”, such as Newsmonster (newsmonster.org, Plattform-unabhängig), NewzCrawler (newzcrawler.com, Windows) oder NetNewsWire (ranchero.com, Mac). On my Powerbook I prefer the latter in its new incarnation “NetNewswire 2.</description></item><item><title>Visit my friends virtually</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-10-10-visit-my-friends-virtually/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2004 08:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-10-10-visit-my-friends-virtually/</guid><description>Two new – and long awaited *g* – releases of websites: My former flat-mate Sebastian alias macsepp relaunched macsepp.com in a very nice css-only design and a rockin’ navigation-scheme. I wish I also had such a worked out “about”-section. He uses TextPattern, a promising and simple CMS (textpattern.com) – I’ll stick with Typo3 though, even if it drives me CRAZY most of the times ;) Along with this, his g/f Eva published her website with very clean colors, though lacking a bit of content (sidekick to eva* *g*).</description></item><item><title>shutdown -h now!</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-10-10-shutdown-h-now/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2004 08:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-10-10-shutdown-h-now/</guid><description>Whew, what a geeky weekend: I was in Berlin all the time, well…over internet-console. Certain circumstances (and a notion of self-destruction) brought me to reinstall my root-server at Strato/Berlin, complete with nine (partly commercial) websites and loads of email-adresses on it. Its about every webmasters nightmare, and took me one day preperation (backup, user-accounts, etc) and even more for the new setup. So, again a weekend lost to web-work – which happens too often in the last months.</description></item><item><title>Helvetica R.I.P.</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-10-01-helvetica-rip/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 22:46:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-10-01-helvetica-rip/</guid><description>I am in process of compiling some pdf-sheets for my applications (vita, short portfolio), which need a worked-out typography. I’ve done some searching for font-alternatives to the omnipresent Helvetica-Typeface – and found “Leapfrogging the classics” on underconsideration.com (nice design, btw). Check out the comments as well, lots of experienced guys in there. Short list of the supposed Helvetica-Killers: Gotham, Interstate, Hoefler Text (to be contd.). Have to stick to Helvetica for floating-text-webdesign though…sigh</description></item><item><title>Updates!</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-09-29-updates/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2004 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-09-29-updates/</guid><description>After finishing the chillu.com-redesign in late june I was really busy with several projects. Most of them are already in the works-section, but they will be subject of a different post (too tired now). So…again under pressure: Applications for my internship in 2005 are in their making, and chillu.com will be my showcase – finally it’s useful to have a website :D On the updates: IE-users rejoice! If you are not already cut off from the internet by dialers, worms or malicous JPEG-Image (lol, by the way), you now get the full functionality in the “works”-section (fixed some javascript-errors).</description></item><item><title>A Man and his playlists</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-09-28-a-man-and-his-playlists/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2004 12:54:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-09-28-a-man-and-his-playlists/</guid><description>Sometimes every computeruser is faced with decisions – tonight with 917 to be precise. Being awake with too much coffee and full-moon I battled against a fierce enemy: the rest of my untagged MP3-collection. With over 900 ratings per hour (or 15 ratings a minute whohoo) I am now proud owner of a completely tagged list! This might sound geeky, but there are a lot of guys out there that would envy me about it *g*.</description></item><item><title>Finally online</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-07-12-finally-online/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2004 11:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-07-12-finally-online/</guid><description>A study-project kinda forced me to finish off the chillu.com-redesign – and here it is! Colours are a more vivid and friendly that in the night-theme of the old version. In general everything is polished a bit: All content is generated by the Content-Management-System Typo3, the Portfolio-Section is updated and beefed up. Browser-Optimization is not yet finshed (problems with IE5 and IE6 *sigh). Apart from that: Mi casa es su casa!</description></item><item><title>Website Prototype</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-04-24-website-prototype/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2004 05:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2004/2004-04-24-website-prototype/</guid><description>The Website-Prototype for a newly-structured chillu.com seems to approach the end! With quite some work I tried to persuade Typo3 to give me DAMN CONTROL over layout and positioning of the page elements back. I didn’t lose this fight, but I’m far from winning either. Whatever…</description></item></channel></rss>