<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ingo Schommer</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/</link><description>Recent content on Ingo Schommer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.chillu.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Silverstripe CMS: Where is 5.x, or how to innovate on a monolith</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2021/silverstripe-where-is-5x/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2021/silverstripe-where-is-5x/</guid><description>Originally posted on silverstripe.org
At Silverstripe Ltd, we&amp;rsquo;ve been mapping out how we can help developers innovate around Silverstripe CMS. Coordinating with the Silverstripe CMS Core Committers, we wanted to bring you an update on Silverstripe CMS and its future. We see the CMS as a platform for innovation with a lean and modular core, leaving opportunities for the ecosystem to thrive on those foundations while keeping CMS 4.x projects sustainable long-term.</description></item><item><title>Contributions to Silverstripe CMS</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/silverstripe/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/silverstripe/</guid><description>Contributed nearly a thousand pull requests and collaborated with hundreds of community members on the many repos making up Silverstripe CMS (PHP and Javascript). Check the github.com/silverstripe contribution timeline.</description></item><item><title>Talk: StripeCon 2020 - Github Issue Relevancy Predictions</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2020/talk-stripecon-2020/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2020/talk-stripecon-2020/</guid><description>Machine learning experiment, creating personalised predictions using Fast.AI, Pytorch, Pandas, Flask (Python).
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ujv2kkmaTLE</description></item><item><title>Supporting you in dependency vulnerability checks</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2020/dependency-vulnerability-checks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2020/dependency-vulnerability-checks/</guid><description>Originally posted on silverstripe.org
Silverstripe CMS supports developers in secure coding practices and website owners in running secure websites and applications. A big part of this is rigour around security releases of our supported modules and communicating the impact of any vulnerabilities found there (see last year’s blog post: A better security classification for supported modules). But any website with our CMS will also pull in community modules as well as other dependencies not managed by us and dependencies which aren’t even in the PHP ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Github Issue Ml Relevancy</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/github-issue-ml-relevancy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/github-issue-ml-relevancy/</guid><description>https://github.com/chillu/github-issue-ml-relevancy
Too many Github notifications, too little time. The obvious answer there is to spend lots of time creating a hyper personalised prediction engine that can tell me what I&amp;rsquo;m interested in. And learn a whole bunch of stuff on the way. This is a tongue-in-cheek experiment, which resulted in a realisation that I&amp;rsquo;m pretty unpredictable.
See it in action (predictions for the chillu github user):
http://github-issue-ml-relevancy.herokuapp.com
What does this do?</description></item><item><title>New CMS demo for a better evaluator experience</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2019/new-cms-demo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2019/new-cms-demo/</guid><description>Originally posted on silverstripe.org. I&amp;rsquo;ve been the Product Owner and Technical Lead on this project.
Silverstripe CMS offers a flexible solution for your website or application. Its open source and modular DNA provides the best of both worlds for developers and CMS users, with a framework that can be easily adapted to suit your organisation’s needs, and an intuitive user interface that empowers teams to deliver great content. So you can easily evaluate what Silverstripe CMS offers, we’ve just launched a new demo that includes a robust set of features, providing a more comprehensive experience than the old open source demo.</description></item><item><title>A better security classification for supported modules</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2019/better-security-classification/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2019/better-security-classification/</guid><description>Originally posted on silverstripe.org
SilverStripe has published security releases for many years, with a well defined security release process. Each security issue we’ve identified was assigned an identifier, and a severity rating. Both of these were custom markers which we’ve applied based on our context. We’re adjusting this to be more in-line with large open source projects, which are depended on by thousands of organisations around the globe. We are also taking this opportunity to redefine how security fixes are handled in “Limited Support” release lines such as SilverStripe 3.</description></item><item><title>Github Issue Tracker</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/silverstripe-issue-tracker/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/silverstripe-issue-tracker/</guid><description>VueJS frontend to aggregate Github issues through their GraphQL API, deployed on Vercel</description></item><item><title>Property Trends Analysis Dashboard</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/property-trends-dashboard/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/property-trends-dashboard/</guid><description>https://github.com/chillu/property-viewer-shiny-dashboard
Applied data analysis to my own house hunting back in 2018. I choose to believe this was a factor in not over-paying for the house we bought (if that is even possible in the New Zealand market&amp;hellip;).
This dashboard is built on Shiny and the R programming language (a proud New Zealand invention!).
Features Interactive map with dot size mapped to sales price, and dot colour mapped to &amp;ldquo;% over RV&amp;rdquo; Filter by neighbourhood Filter by property attributes like floor space or RV Browse tabular data for max.</description></item><item><title>Headless CMS: The future of content delivery</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2018/future-of-content-delivery/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2018/future-of-content-delivery/</guid><description>Originally posted on silverstripe.org
When we talk about the future of content delivery, we’re interested with how content and data will be published on websites and what advances in web technologies will make this more effective for teams. We introduced a few of these concepts as part of a recent meetup for the Common Web Platform (CWP) community. SilverStripe Solution Architect Ingo Schommer previously covered headless CMS in a great technical overview, this post however looks at the same topic but how it relates to marketers and content teams.</description></item><item><title>Alexa Skill for New Zealand Earthquakes</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/alexa-skill-kiwi-quakes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/alexa-skill-kiwi-quakes/</guid><description>https://github.com/chillu/alexa-skill-kiwi-quakes
New Zealanders often ask themselves: Was that an earthquake, a truck going past, or just the wind? Now you can ask Alexa!
&amp;ldquo;Alexa, ask kiwi quakes if this was an earthquake&amp;rdquo;
Under the hood, it uses AWS Lambda functions deployed through the Serverless Framework.
I should acknowledge the awesome New Zealand GeoNet project and its sponsors EQC, GNS Science and LINZ, for providing data used in this app.</description></item><item><title>Arduino Led Scarf</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/arduino-led-scarf/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/arduino-led-scarf/</guid><description>https://github.com/chillu/arduino-led-scarf
An art project was for Kiwiburn 2016 and 2017, the regional Burning Man in New Zealand. An Arduino Nano powers LEDs in a fully scarf and stylish top hat, with buttons for mode controls. Comes with click-based beat matching and various &amp;ldquo;drop modes&amp;rdquo; for maximum awesomeness on electronic music.
This project taught me how to work within tiny compute constraints, and how unproductive coding in raw C can be! But it also gave me an appreciation for hardware product design.</description></item><item><title>Github Contribution Dashboard</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/github-dashing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/github-dashing/</guid><description>https://github.com/chillu/github-dashing
Dashboard to monitor the health of github projects based on their contribution statistics. Based on the Dashing framework (written in Ruby). This was used for a few years at the Silverstripe offices in Wellington, as an information radiator. In hindsight, the leaderboard surfaced some hidden heroes, but also incentivised less productive behaviours. The build dashboard was a game changer, given the extremely large amount of codebases supported by the teams it focused us on quality (or at least figuring out why builds are fragile&amp;hellip;).</description></item><item><title>Book: Silverstripe - The Complete Guide to CMS Development</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/silverstripe-book/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/silverstripe-book/</guid><description>Authored the first (paper!) book about Silverstripe CMS, with thousands of copies sold. The book was originally co-authored with Steven Broschart, and published in Germany for Galileo Computing.</description></item></channel></rss>