<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>serverless on chillu.com</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/tags/serverless/</link><description>Recent content in serverless on chillu.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.chillu.com/tags/serverless/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Github Issue Ml Relevancy</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/github-issue-ml-relevancy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/github-issue-ml-relevancy/</guid><description>https://github.com/chillu/github-issue-ml-relevancy
Too many Github notifications, too little time. The obvious answer there is to spend lots of time creating a hyper personalised prediction engine that can tell me what I&amp;rsquo;m interested in. And learn a whole bunch of stuff on the way. This is a tongue-in-cheek experiment, which resulted in a realisation that I&amp;rsquo;m pretty unpredictable.
See it in action (predictions for the chillu github user):
http://github-issue-ml-relevancy.herokuapp.com
What does this do?</description></item><item><title>Github Issue Tracker</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/silverstripe-issue-tracker/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/silverstripe-issue-tracker/</guid><description>VueJS frontend to aggregate Github issues through their GraphQL API, deployed on Vercel</description></item><item><title>Alexa Skill for New Zealand Earthquakes</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/alexa-skill-kiwi-quakes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/alexa-skill-kiwi-quakes/</guid><description>https://github.com/chillu/alexa-skill-kiwi-quakes
New Zealanders often ask themselves: Was that an earthquake, a truck going past, or just the wind? Now you can ask Alexa!
&amp;ldquo;Alexa, ask kiwi quakes if this was an earthquake&amp;rdquo;
Under the hood, it uses AWS Lambda functions deployed through the Serverless Framework.
I should acknowledge the awesome New Zealand GeoNet project and its sponsors EQC, GNS Science and LINZ, for providing data used in this app.</description></item><item><title>Echt: A social network based on face recognition</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/echt-face-recognition-social-network/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/echt-face-recognition-social-network/</guid><description>On Github: server and client
Worked with my good friend @bnolan to realise his idea for a minimalistic social network based on selfies and facial recognition. In short, you join by taking a photo, and you &amp;ldquo;friend&amp;rdquo; someone by taking a selfie with them. Being physically in the same space with the other person is a feature, not a bug. We&amp;rsquo;ve taken this idea to PoC stage and tested it with a few friends, before it lost steam.</description></item><item><title>Talk: GraphQL in SilverStripe - Reasons and Demo App (Stripecon Malta 2017)</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2017/talk-stripecon-eu-2017/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2017/talk-stripecon-eu-2017/</guid><description>Talk at Stripecon Malta in 2017. I&amp;rsquo;ve built a PoC, demonstrating the new GraphQL module exposing Silverstripe CMS data through a simple app built on React Apollo, and deployed on Zeit (which has been rebranded to Vercel).
See slides and talk recording.</description></item></channel></rss>