<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Ingo Schommer</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Ingo Schommer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.chillu.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Silverstripe CMS: Where is 5.x, or how to innovate on a monolith</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2021/silverstripe-where-is-5x/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2021/silverstripe-where-is-5x/</guid><description>Originally posted on silverstripe.org
At Silverstripe Ltd, we&amp;rsquo;ve been mapping out how we can help developers innovate around Silverstripe CMS. Coordinating with the Silverstripe CMS Core Committers, we wanted to bring you an update on Silverstripe CMS and its future. We see the CMS as a platform for innovation with a lean and modular core, leaving opportunities for the ecosystem to thrive on those foundations while keeping CMS 4.x projects sustainable long-term.</description></item><item><title>Talk: StripeCon 2020 - Github Issue Relevancy Predictions</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2020/talk-stripecon-2020/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2020/talk-stripecon-2020/</guid><description>Machine learning experiment, creating personalised predictions using Fast.AI, Pytorch, Pandas, Flask (Python).
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ujv2kkmaTLE</description></item><item><title>Supporting you in dependency vulnerability checks</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2020/dependency-vulnerability-checks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2020/dependency-vulnerability-checks/</guid><description>Originally posted on silverstripe.org
Silverstripe CMS supports developers in secure coding practices and website owners in running secure websites and applications. A big part of this is rigour around security releases of our supported modules and communicating the impact of any vulnerabilities found there (see last year’s blog post: A better security classification for supported modules). But any website with our CMS will also pull in community modules as well as other dependencies not managed by us and dependencies which aren’t even in the PHP ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>New CMS demo for a better evaluator experience</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2019/new-cms-demo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2019/new-cms-demo/</guid><description>Originally posted on silverstripe.org. I&amp;rsquo;ve been the Product Owner and Technical Lead on this project.
Silverstripe CMS offers a flexible solution for your website or application. Its open source and modular DNA provides the best of both worlds for developers and CMS users, with a framework that can be easily adapted to suit your organisation’s needs, and an intuitive user interface that empowers teams to deliver great content. So you can easily evaluate what Silverstripe CMS offers, we’ve just launched a new demo that includes a robust set of features, providing a more comprehensive experience than the old open source demo.</description></item><item><title>A better security classification for supported modules</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2019/better-security-classification/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2019/better-security-classification/</guid><description>Originally posted on silverstripe.org
SilverStripe has published security releases for many years, with a well defined security release process. Each security issue we’ve identified was assigned an identifier, and a severity rating. Both of these were custom markers which we’ve applied based on our context. We’re adjusting this to be more in-line with large open source projects, which are depended on by thousands of organisations around the globe. We are also taking this opportunity to redefine how security fixes are handled in “Limited Support” release lines such as SilverStripe 3.</description></item><item><title>Headless CMS: The future of content delivery</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2018/future-of-content-delivery/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2018/future-of-content-delivery/</guid><description>Originally posted on silverstripe.org
When we talk about the future of content delivery, we’re interested with how content and data will be published on websites and what advances in web technologies will make this more effective for teams. We introduced a few of these concepts as part of a recent meetup for the Common Web Platform (CWP) community. SilverStripe Solution Architect Ingo Schommer previously covered headless CMS in a great technical overview, this post however looks at the same topic but how it relates to marketers and content teams.</description></item></channel></rss>