<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>data on chillu.com</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/tags/data/</link><description>Recent content in data on chillu.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 16:26:05 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.chillu.com/tags/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Analysing community health via Google BigQuery</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2021/telling-stories-with-data/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 16:26:05 +1200</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2021/telling-stories-with-data/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a steward for a reasonably large open source community (Silverstripe CMS) for over a decade. My various roles working at the main sponsor of this community (Silverstripe Ltd) put me in a privileged position to talk to many awesome folks in this community, and influence the direction of the product. But along the way, I&amp;rsquo;ve also accumulated a lot of anecdotes, bias and gut feel about the &amp;ldquo;shape&amp;rdquo; of our community and its contributions.</description></item><item><title>Talk: StripeCon 2020 - Github Issue Relevancy Predictions</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2020/talk-stripecon-2020/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2020/talk-stripecon-2020/</guid><description>Machine learning experiment, creating personalised predictions using Fast.AI, Pytorch, Pandas, Flask (Python).
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ujv2kkmaTLE</description></item><item><title>Property Trends Analysis Dashboard</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/property-trends-dashboard/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/property-trends-dashboard/</guid><description>https://github.com/chillu/property-viewer-shiny-dashboard
Applied data analysis to my own house hunting back in 2018. I choose to believe this was a factor in not over-paying for the house we bought (if that is even possible in the New Zealand market&amp;hellip;).
This dashboard is built on Shiny and the R programming language (a proud New Zealand invention!).
Features Interactive map with dot size mapped to sales price, and dot colour mapped to &amp;ldquo;% over RV&amp;rdquo; Filter by neighbourhood Filter by property attributes like floor space or RV Browse tabular data for max.</description></item><item><title>Alexa Skill for New Zealand Earthquakes</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/alexa-skill-kiwi-quakes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/alexa-skill-kiwi-quakes/</guid><description>https://github.com/chillu/alexa-skill-kiwi-quakes
New Zealanders often ask themselves: Was that an earthquake, a truck going past, or just the wind? Now you can ask Alexa!
&amp;ldquo;Alexa, ask kiwi quakes if this was an earthquake&amp;rdquo;
Under the hood, it uses AWS Lambda functions deployed through the Serverless Framework.
I should acknowledge the awesome New Zealand GeoNet project and its sponsors EQC, GNS Science and LINZ, for providing data used in this app.</description></item><item><title>Github Contribution Dashboard</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/github-dashing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/github-dashing/</guid><description>https://github.com/chillu/github-dashing
Dashboard to monitor the health of github projects based on their contribution statistics. Based on the Dashing framework (written in Ruby). This was used for a few years at the Silverstripe offices in Wellington, as an information radiator. In hindsight, the leaderboard surfaced some hidden heroes, but also incentivised less productive behaviours. The build dashboard was a game changer, given the extremely large amount of codebases supported by the teams it focused us on quality (or at least figuring out why builds are fragile&amp;hellip;).</description></item></channel></rss>