<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>diy on chillu.com</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/tags/diy/</link><description>Recent content in diy on chillu.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.chillu.com/tags/diy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Arduino Led Scarf</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/projects/arduino-led-scarf/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/projects/arduino-led-scarf/</guid><description>https://github.com/chillu/arduino-led-scarf
An art project was for Kiwiburn 2016 and 2017, the regional Burning Man in New Zealand. An Arduino Nano powers LEDs in a fully scarf and stylish top hat, with buttons for mode controls. Comes with click-based beat matching and various &amp;ldquo;drop modes&amp;rdquo; for maximum awesomeness on electronic music. Got lots of advice on transistors from @sminnee and @stojg, and help in wrangling C from @bnolan.
This project taught me how to work within tiny compute constraints, and how unproductive coding in raw C can be!</description></item><item><title>DIY work setup: A combined sitting and standing desk</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2013/2013-02-16-diy-work-setup-a-combined-sitting-and-standing-desk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2013 19:44:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2013/2013-02-16-diy-work-setup-a-combined-sitting-and-standing-desk/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a sloucher with terrible posture, and I would like to keep working in my sedentary profession of a programmer for quite a while. Current research suggests that sitting all day isn&amp;rsquo;t good for you (nytimes.com). Standing all day isn&amp;rsquo;t ideal either. I&amp;rsquo;m also a passionate DIYer. So I set out and built myself a standing and sitting desk, combining the best of both worlds.
Disclaimer: I&amp;rsquo;m not studied in ergonomics, and just documenting a setup which has worked for me for about half a year now.</description></item><item><title>Indoor gardening with a window farm</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2012/2012-04-22-photo-post/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2012 19:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2012/2012-04-22-photo-post/</guid><description>After being inspired by a TED talk about window farms, I decided to build my own! I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a tinkerer, and like greens around me. One day I&amp;rsquo;ll have an awesome veggie garden, but for now a window farm is the best option for our small city apartment. So why not just put plants on the window sill? Its just more space saving with a window farm, as you use less room for containers through hydroponics and efficient continuous watering.</description></item><item><title>The €2 Laptop Stand</title><link>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2007/2007-10-03-the-2-laptop-stand/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2007 05:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.chillu.com/posts/2007/2007-10-03-the-2-laptop-stand/</guid><description>Update (04/10/2007): This article has been lifehacked. Thanks for all your comments!
Being a programmer, I crouch in front of computers a lot – obviously you want to avoid being a cripple with 30 and get an ergonomic workplace. Usually this means having a separately adjustable keyboard and screen in addition to my Macbook Pro. Currently i don’t have this luxury, so I came up with a really simple laptop stand to rise the screen-height and have a more relaxed wrist position.</description></item></channel></rss>